Naserian Ruth Munkushi

naserianmunkushi@gmail.com | (712) 578-8550 | Nairobi | https://www.linkedin.com/in/ruth-naserian/ https://github.com/MunkushiR

SUMMARY

Dedicated Software Engineer with 1 year of experience in developing, optimizing, and securing ICT systems; seeking a Software Developer role. Excelled in backend development, enhanced system efficiency, and reduced security incidents by 25%. Trained in advanced user support, technical documentation, and system integration.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MURANG'A COUNTY

Software Engineer

Jan 2024 - Present

- Develop an automated E-meeting system to streamline meeting notifications and document distribution.
- Train and maintain the Health Management System for improved healthcare data management.
- · Design and implement robust ICT infrastructure, achieving high availability and system optimization.
- Implement network security protocols, notably an Intrusion Detection System, to reduce security incidents.

ITALANTA

Junior Software Engineer

Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

- Participated in the design and development of a backend system for a high-traffic website, optimizing performance and improving efficiency.
- Contributed to the enhancement of website functionality, resulting in a notable increase in system responsiveness and user satisfaction.
- Accelerated project timelines, achieving a 25% reduction in time to completion for key deliverables.

MINISTRY OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT

ICT Officer

May 2022 - Aug 2022

- Developed and executed ICT infrastructure upgrades, achieving 99% system availability, and increased operational
 efficiency by 20%.
- Managed the configuration and integration of over 50 IT devices, ensuring compatibility and seamless functionality within the network.
- Rolled out an Intrusion Detection System (IDS), resulting in a 25% reduction in security incidents and bolstering system defenses.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF EASTERN AFRICA, BARATON

Aug 2023

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering

MORINGA SCHOOL

Sep 2023

Software Engineering

POWER LEARN PROJECT

ONGOING

Software Engineering

ALX AI Career Essentials **ENROLLED**

CERTIFICATIONS

Cyber Security Essentials, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure

SKILLS

 $SQL \bullet Python \bullet Streamlit \bullet HTML \bullet CSS \bullet Data \ Collection \bullet Data \ Analysis \bullet Machine \ Learning \bullet IT \ Support \bullet IT \ Automation \bullet Figma \bullet Front-end \ and \ Back-end \ Development$